HATIM ALATTAS

Software Engineer

+966 56 613 1333

@ alattas96@outlook.com

@ www.hatimalattas.com

Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

SUMMARY

I am a self-motivated software engineer who enjoys solving problems and building web applications! I merge a passion for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create cool digital experiences. My repertoire includes programming languages and tools such as Python, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Bootstrap and more.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Participant)

Misk Academy - General Assembly

11/2019 - 02/2020

General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive is a full-time career accelerator that's designed to transform students from novices to job-ready, full-stack software engineers

- Built the famous game Connect 4, a front-end web application that users can see and interact with, leveraging JavaScript, jQuery HTML, and CSS
- * Built a full-stack application using Ruby on Rails framework that authenticates users and allows them to review stadiums and stores data in MySQL database system
- Developed the front-end using ReactJS for a full-stack application called Menu App, which is a platform to present restaurants menus for viewers to check the desired restaurant menu
- Developed the front-end and the back-end using React and Express to build GetFit App, which is a full-stack application to present information related to health, diets, workouts, products, where the user can set goals and calculate calories intake

Software Developer (Research Internship)

Ryerson University

1 06/2018 - 09/2018 **♀** Toronto

Mitacs Globalink Research Internship is a competitive initiative for international undergraduates from Brazil, China, India, Mexico, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, and Vietnam

Project Title: Further development of graphical structural analysis software using C++ language

- Successfully modeled axially-loaded circular columns subjected to lateral impact loads due to accidental ship collisions
- Verified the developed computer models using experimental results available in the literature

AWARDS



Dean's Honor List



Superior Certificate



Excellent Grade with Second Class Honors



4th place in the **Mathematics** Excellence Competition

LANGUAGES

Arabic

Native ••••

English

Fluent ••••

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End

JavaScript

jQuery

Bootstrap 4

React|S

HTML5

CSS3

Back End

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

MySQL

NodeJS (ExpressJS)

Python (Flask)

Ruby (Ruby on Rails)

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive Program

Misk Academy - General Assembly

2019 - 2020

- Requirements included the attendance of 480 hours of face-to-face instruction, completion of course projects, as well as the successful completion of the capstone presentation
- Key Course Topics: Application Programming, Problem Solving Strategies, Git, Github, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, React, RESTful API, Full Stack Development and Deployment, Authentication and Authorization, Algorithms, Data structure, Design Patterns and Presentation Skills

Full Stack Developer Nanodegree Program Misk Academy - Udacity

₩ 2020

• The goal of the Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree program is to equip learners with the unique skills they need to build database-backed APIs and web applications

BS in Electrical & Computer Engineering

University of Jeddah

2014 - 2019

Senior Design Project: Designed a control system that can decide the number of air conditioners that should be operating based on the number of people inside a building using Arduino, Photoresistor, and RF Transceiver

4.5 / 5.0

Elective Courses: Computer Programming, Computer Networks, Digital Logic Design, Control Systems, Microprocessors & Microcontrollers